i would like to give you a tiny
introduction to the core concepts of
object-oriented programming the way i
would have liked to learn them when i
was learning to code object-oriented
programming is a program paradigm which
is basically a way of organizing your
code a way of thinking and structuring
your data it's actually very very
popular because some of the most
dominant programming languages like
c-sharp and java that have huge
communities and very big enterprise
adoption are object oriented languages
and it's even more popular because
programming languages like javascript
and python that are not specifically
object oriented support most of the
object oriented features required to
write object-oriented code this means
that if you learn how to do
object-oriented programming or oop you
are going to be able to transfer your
skills to a wide array of languages you
can move from java to typescript and
c-sharp very very easy i would say that
learning oop is very very easy because
humans intuitively think in an
object-oriented way you will see what
that means by the end of this video i
promise so let's get started what we're
going to do now is we're going to
pretend that we are going to create a
video game if we're creating a video
game we would need to create a player
object this player object is the one
that is going to hold the data of our
players and in javascript code it could
look something like this creating
players like this it's okay when we only
have to create one player the problem
happens when this number starts to grow
when we have more players as you can see
we can see some patterns starting to
emerge but also some issues the patterns
are that for example as you can see
these players all share the same
properties they all have name health and
skill
the only difference between them is the
data the issue here as you can see is
that there is nobody telling us that we
should have a specific shape of what
makes up a player we could make a
mistake when we are creating a player
and we might forget to add skills to one
player or we might misspell a property
and those misspelling errors might be
very hard to catch for example somewhere
in this code i put some silly spelling
mistakes that i am 100 going to make and
they will be very very hard to find at a
first glance another problem of
duplicating code and creating players in
this way is the fact that if for example
i want to create a new property let's
say experience points and i want to add
experience points to all my players i
will have to search in my code for all
the player objects that i created and i
would have to add the experience points
property one by one
that does not sound like a good idea a
better idea would be to have a player
factory some function or something where
i can just input some data and i can
receive a player object as output this
means i wouldn't have to duplicate so
much code and i will minimize spelling
mistakes also this means that if we
wanted to add the experience points
property to all our players i just have
to modify
one place and that is the player factory
if i modify the player factory then all
the players will be updated as well and
this is when i want to introduce the
cornerstone of oop and that is the
concept of classes classes allow us to
create factories for objects that have
the same properties but different data
classes allow us to define a shape a
blueprint of how our player object
should look like now the cool examples
on this video are on javascript and
python if you don't know javascript or
python and you want to learn to code for
free with me with subtitles in hangul
then please click the link below there
you will find an eight hour free
javascript course and a five hour free
python course that i'm going to update
very very soon please check out the link
below if you already know javascript and
python but you want to learn things like
react.js react native go redox graphql
for free click the link below because we
have courses on those things as well
using classes our code will look
something like this now don't worry
we're going to see what constructure and
init means and does later for now let's
focus on the result let's focus on how
beautiful and easy the code becomes when
we want to create new players as we can
see we don't have to copy paste as much
as before and just like if we were
talking about objects we can access
their properties as well as you can see
the player class is a blueprint is a
mode is the factory that allows us to
create player objects that all have the
same properties but different data you
can think of classes like cookie cutters
they are the template that we use to
mold our data in whatever shape we want
when we use a class like for example
when we create an elon using the player
cookie cutter
we refer to elon as an instance or an
object of the player class instances or
objects are the cookies that we get
after we use the cookie cutter but let's
go back to the code and now see that in
the javascript class there is something
called constructure and in the python
class there is something called init
these things are normal functions as you
can see but because they are inside of
classes we don't call them functions we
call them methods instead the
constructor and the init methods are
called automatically by javascript in
python when we create a new object from
a class in the constructor method is
where you can choose how to construct
your class what properties is it going
to have
as you can see our constructor methods
take arguments just like a function does
this is why i can say new player and
then i write elon musk which will be the
first argument which will be the name of
the player then i write the health and
then i write the skill but also as you
can see we can choose to program all our
players to always start their experience
points on xero the word this or self is
how we can refer to properties and
methods inside of the player class it is
very easy to read as well we can say
that this player has a property called
xp for experience points and its initial
value is 0. so far as you can see
classes are pretty cool they allow us to
create factories or cookie cutters for
objects with the same shapes we also saw
that classes have methods inside of them
and methods are the things that take
classes to the next level apart from the
constructor an innit method a class
could have as many methods as we need
for example we can create a method to
teach our players to say hello now all
the objects created using the player
class will be able to call the say hello
method or if we were creating a combat
game for example we could create a
method to program what happens when a
player takes a hit as you can see
methods make our classes way smarter
than before before we're using classes
to just organize data but now with
methods we can specify interfaces of how
to manipulate and how to read data to
finish this intro let's take a look at a
very important oop concept called
inheritance inheritance allows us to
reduce code duplication and divide our
code in many reusable pieces in the
offline world inheritance happens when
the parents die and the kids get all
their money in the object-oriented world
nobody dies but the child's classes get
all the properties of the father classes
if we were making a game like the sims
for example which is a people simulator
we will need to start with a class for a
human but we would also need a baby
class that is a human that is cute and
knows how to cry and maybe we need a
teenager class that is a human and then
knows how to curse as you can see there
is some code duplication going on here
even though all the classes are a little
bit different they all share the fact
that they are all human they all have a
name two arms and two legs and this is
when inheritance comes into play instead
of writing down this that name these
that arms and these that legs in every
class that we create we can instead
extend from a class that has these that
name these that arms and these that lex
and that class is human so the code
would look something like this when we
say that the baby class or the teenager
class extend from human what we are
saying is that we want baby and teenager
to have all the properties that human
has plus their own properties as well so
this means that a baby instance will
have a name legs and arms it will also
be cute and you will know how to cry but
this code doesn't really work yet and
the reason why it doesn't work yet is
because if we think about it the human
constructor is the one that says the
name of the human according to the
constructor arguments but we are not
creating humans directly instead we are
creating babies and teenagers to call
the constructor method of the human
class from the baby and teenager classes
we have to call the super method from
the constructor of the baby and teenager
classes and everything will work well
and that's it for this video as you can
see the way we model our data the way we
access it and the way we manipulate it
in the object-oriented programming world
is very comfortable and i hope that by
now you can see why oop is so popular
and why so many people like it this is
not all of course this is just a tiny
introduction to oop and these are the
concepts that i think you are going to
be able to use everywhere across any oop
programming language after this if you
want to dive deeper into oop you need to
learn about private public and protected
methods and properties you also need to
learn what are abstract classes static
methods and it will be very useful to
learn what interfaces do as well i on
purpose did not want to use words like
abstraction encapsulation and
polymorphism in this video because i
wanted to focus more on the practical
aspect of oop and how it can improve our
code if you would like me to do a more
theory video of oop then please let me
know in the comments i'm going to be
looking at them right now and also if
you are waiting for the second video of
the functional programming series don't
worry because it's coming as well i
wanted to make this oop video first
because we're going to be comparing
functional programming with oop a lot so
we have to basically know the enemy
first thank you stay happy stay free eat
kimchi ham something heyo see you on the
next one bye